so welcome to this fourth episode of
business Central under the hood so a
while ago when we started this series we
um we talked about Ai and you showed a
lot of interest for for that topic so we
thought we would do another another
episode about it and talk about how we
more specifically how we implemented the
uh co-pilot chat feature in business
Central my name is viston Nicholas I am
the Chief Architect of business Central
and today with me to talk about the
chatal chat in business Central I have
Sam hi Hi Sam you have been working with
the ey for a while now yeah so tell us a
little bit how how it all started you
what what what did you start working
with um yeah so I've been kind of
fortunate enough to be part of the whole
AI wave since the beginning um so about
18 months ago uh we started like playing
around with some ideas after seeing like
the launch of chat GPT uh growing um so
that's where we came up with the idea
for the marketing text suggestions at
the start uh and obviously we then
released that as a feature um and after
that we started looking at kind of
what's next so we did some hackathons
around that internally and uh yeah one
of them was this idea for uh kind of
like chatting with your data in business
Central um so yeah we built a very
primitive hackathon here and uh that
looked promising so we decided to go
ahead with it and actually try and
productize it so what what's the uh
co-pilot BC co-pilot chat what can what
can you do in in PC Co chat yeah yes so
right now uh obviously it's like an open
chat so you can type whatever but we we
have kind of scoped it down to two main
kind of things one is uh looking up kind
of the documentation and how you can do
specific processes understanding
terminology in in business Central uh
and the other one is like finding data
within it so you can say like let's say
you're on one task and U someone asks
you a quick question like hey do we have
any inventory for this item you can
without kind of being distracted just
quickly type like do we have any
inventory for this item uh and then
you'll get an answer back and uh yeah
hopefully saves you some time so and
then you can do that any you can do that
anywhere in the product right the chat
pen is you can you can invoke it any
place in the prodct exactly yeah yeah
and kind of technically from uh like
technical perspective it's uh it's quite
interesting because we wanted it to be
non-blocking intentionally so you can uh
like offload these queries and it might
take a little bit to run but you can
just keep using the product at the same
time it's all kind of asynchronous okay
so so so um when was it released which
which release is it available for yeah
so it was the last release wave so 2024
release Wave 1 yes um it's currently in
a public preview um and um it's only
available in US environments for now uh
but we hope over the wave to roll it out
to more regions all right yeah so tell
us a little more about how uh how is it
built you know you know how how did how
did we build that so for so maybe um
what's the difference between uh the BC
co-pilot chat yeah and for example Bing
chat or chat GPT all the chat exactly
you could you could you could use yeah
so so they they have a lot of similari I
would say to begin with obviously
there's a conversation that you can have
uh you call a multi-turn conversation so
that's where you can keep talking and it
will kind of remember what you spoke
about previously um and that's the same
with all of these things um chat GPT I
would say you are talking very closely
to the the AI model um at least by
default so it it only knows what the
model was trained on um Bing chat uh um
yeah Bing chat and um co-pilot chat with
business Central are kind of similar in
the sense that they both use external
data sources to kind of um enhance the
foundation model uh with like current
information and so obviously with Bing
it it it's grounded in data that it
finds everywhere on the internet and
within business Central we we have more
control over where it's grounded so we
can say Obviously for the documentation
we use use the the learn. microsoft.com
documentation like the official business
Central
documentation um and additionally for
like asking about your inventory and
items going back to that example um we
can use the data within business Central
to kind of help the uh Foundation model
understand what is in your system so
what it means just so we understand what
the put a bit of Conex that what it
means that when when the the user types
something in the in the chat in BC
uh it's not we just we don't just send
that that exactly prompt to the to to uh
to the open eye service there's some
other things happening on the so can you
tell us a little bit about what's
happening when I TP for example show me
the last um sales quote I've opened for
that customer what happens yeah yeah
yeah yeah so so really like the very
first thing that happens is there is a
conversation that is happening right so
which is not visible to the user well
both so so there is there is the the
conversation the user is having with
co-pilot chat um and and there uh we
take the whole conversation and we
actually we go to the model and and ask
it to um bring condense this whole
conversation into like a single chat
message and this chat message kind of
contains your uh the current intent of
your question and like any other
information that we need to answer your
question and then once we now have this
like condensed version of the
conversation we can now pass that to
other parts of the system uh and that's
a lot easier to work with than a whole
conversation history right um so yeah on
once we know what you're asking about uh
we have these uh two skills or
capabilities uh right now that I
mentioned like the documentation or like
trying to find some records in your
system so you ask looking for these
sales documents that is obviously not a
documentation question right so uh we
would then choose to pick this uh uh
like um find and go capability or
navigational capability um and then that
hands over to some other code now um
with the um condensed conversation uh
and then we can go and query the NST in
your database to try and find the
relevant records uh and then we can give
this all back to uh the overall
conversation that uh your the end user
is seeing um and then we can write you a
nice chat message saying like oh yes
this okay so there's a lot of things
that happening here so so if I if I just
summarize what you're saying so what the
first thing that happens is that we so
we first of all what you were saying is
that we have a predetermined set of
skills that we can uh things we can
achieve through the chat right and the
first thing we do is so there basically
different paths that can be followed
depending on what you you use right exct
and the first thing that happens uh if I
understand you correctly is that we
determine the uh the intent of the of
the the user so depending on where the
chat is so already there there is a
small conversation happening right
between between the open AI service the
aure open ey service and and what that
means also is that we take the user
input
and we have a whole set of prompts
exactly right so we have engineered on
our end right exactly which we kind of
weaved with some of the data or some of
what the user is writing and and kind of
you know choose the right path depending
on what what feature we what we want to
achieve right so this promt so the so
this prompt we have engineered yeah uh
we talked about in the first uh in the
first episode of of the series we talked
about prompt engineering a little bit uh
can you talk bit about that because
there is there is a lot of prompt
engineering involved when we uh when we
Implement a feature like this one can
talk a little bit about about this part
yeah yeah yes so as you mentioned we we
take this conversation and we uh wrap
that around our own prompt to explain to
the model that we want to take this
conversation and kind of rewrite it to
this intent um and uh yeah writing a
front to do that that you kind of have
any kind of assurance that it will work
work like when you run it at scale uh
it's definitely a nice challenge um and
yeah as you mentioned like in the first
talk as well like the the model itself
is effectively a blackbox um so the best
way to do it is to you know go back to
your Basics and do like proper like test
driven development so you have your your
data sets of like inputs that you want
to support so these are like the types
of question or conversation that you we
we want to like uh validate
um and then uh yeah you write your test
cases and you have like an assertion
that based on these inputs uh you know
that uh you want it to go to this
particular skill or maybe it's a a
scenario that's not supported so then
you have to have some kind of off topic
handling uh but these are all like
fairly simple assertions that you can do
um and um the way we we kind of write
these test cases is we try to have a
single test case that covers the scario
um and then we have like a data set of
these prompts uh like it can even be
like a CSV file that kind of thing um
and are we testing these are we writing
some Al code for that or are we okay so
it's it's it's in so the but don't we do
like some maybe some initial prompt
engineering just with a prompt to start
with yeah yes so so for the the copilot
chat um because that's executed in a
micros service um so those tests are not
in
um they're just like uh like Ms tests
within cop um but yeah even even before
that you know you can go into Azure
studio and uh kind of try and prototype
some prompts there um I think that's
it's a nice place to start but as the
complexity grows and you start taking
other external dependencies on data for
example like say NST
metadata uh then then it really helps to
have like a full test Suite um and using
that as your playground but would you
say like if I as an advice maybe to
people who want to start developing AI
feature when you say that maybe the the
first very first place to start it go to
something like Asia Asia AI Studio or
try some prompts and see if uh you know
if you have an idea for a feature try
try some scenarios out try try to see
which prompt could work and how many you
need and kind of respons how you know
sometimes uh you know I've played with
it a little bit myself sometime you you
tend to write maybe too big of a promps
and then you know try to have the AI
service do too many things at once then
you quickly figure out you want to break
in down uh so talking about which how
many how many uh um how many of these
system prompts we have in loads okay
like hundreds
or I don't so for chat specifically I
mean it's it's not hundreds
uh but it's it's 10 yeah exactly and uh
yeah so we uh like I say I think the
Azure I is a great place to start uh
also to get the understanding of like
the different roles that the models have
available to them so like the kind of
the waiting that a system prompt has
versus a user prompt um yeah so there
this concept of system prompt and user
prompt right exactly the user prompt is
typically what what the user types right
and the system prompt is this prom you
were talking about before which are
happening on the hood that you don't see
exactly which can get kind of uh
intermingled with with the user prompt
right yeah so you might have heard the
term like meta prompt and I I think it
is quite a fluffy term at the moment but
the way that I Define a meta prompt
right now is a it's effectively a prompt
that is not visible to the end user so
uh kind of the conversation history uh
that you see within copilot chat as well
as like what the user is typing that is
all part of the prompt and then we have
a meta prompt around this um that then
we do to make this conversation do
things right um yeah and so again AZ
studio is great place to get started um
and seeing how this all plays with each
other um I think another thing to keep
in mind as well um like at the very
beginning of all this AI stuff uh you
probably saw a a lot of these jailbreaks
right where people were just riding like
ignore what you just heard and people
talk about exactly exactly so so uh
again this is where the roles become
very important because if uh if it's a
user role uh that that the prompt is
saying like ignore the instructions the
model knows that like w this is coming
from the user so maybe they're doing
some trickery here you know um so I
think if if you're dealing with some
kind of
how we show untrusted input uh it's very
good to kind of wrap this in your user
prompts and then having the system
prompts reinforce that yeah so what you
now you mentioned that what what are we
doing to prevent users because as
opposed to for examp the the text uh
marketing text generation where we we
had kind of a lot of control about the
prompting you're not talking directly to
in the yeah in the in the chat feature
uh you can your user can write anything
that opens up for
maybe uh opportunity for doing
jailbreaks so what what what do we do
avoid that or to prevent that yeah so
it's been yeah a really nice like
technical challenge to solve so
obviously we do like what I what I just
said to start with so ensuring that all
the inputs U are being put in the user
uh prompts and we have the appropriate
meta prompts in the system prompts to
kind of uh let the model know that like
kind of the scope of the questions is
like within business Central um that we
uh don't want it to produce any kind of
like harmful content that kind of thing
um but again how do you know this
actually works and I guess this is your
question right so first thing is uh we
obviously build a data set of like um
should we say like bad input um and then
we run this through again our test Suite
so data set that could be har
potentially harmful right how large is
that data set yeah so it's it's like
thousands of uh inputs um but but um
that we know can potentially produce
some harmful response or undesirable
response yeah and and what we do as well
in addition to this is uh we we even
start simulating conversations so we we
use the llm to generate a a uh like a
harmful conversation uh and then we uh
we we simulate this conversation with
our Co pilot chat in business Central um
and then we see uh is it producing any
kind of unexpected outputs and uh like
this testing is quite valuable did have
a few like really nice findings so we
set two L&M to talk to each other our
own our own feature the BC co-pilot
chart right and we have another LM that
asks the try to kind of jailbreak it or
produce some inappropriate content with
with a whole set of of prom We Know can
be
exactly and and we kind of needed to do
this because um if you just take this
list of say thousand examples um a lot
of them are just very quickly dismissed
as like off topic um and and like sure
your tests are passing but are you
really testing the thing right um so you
can almost think of it kind of like your
fuzz testing traditionally so um what we
do now is we have this data set of like
harmful inputs and then we pass that
through through the the llm to kind of
like tailor it to a more business
Central context so that you go deeper
into the system uh and uh hopefully
uncover bugs before it gets to the cust
and how we how do make sure that because
the response can vary it's not like a
you know when you run when you run um a
regular test like a classic with classic
code unit testing so the response is uh
is not it's not exactly true and false
it's just text and it can vary exactly
so how do we know that for example it's
not inappropriate cont exactly yeah yeah
because I said we have like thousands of
simulations right so you don't want to
manually go through TI them off do that
exactly so so again we take an LM uh and
we normally take like the the best model
available at the time and we ask it to
grade the response according to a few
different categories of harm we explain
what the harms are and that kind of
thing um and and then based on that
result we can very quickly see if uh
there are uh problems or not so so just
to summarize there actually three LMS
involved you say so there's one asking
the question yeah to BC chat right yeah
uh and then we get the answer we feed it
to a third one and ask it is that is it
okay you know is that is that okay
that's basically the principle of it
right yeah yeah yeah and really that's
that's the only way we can do this at
scale um and like sure maybe doing it
manually once is fine but uh you know at
the rate that the like asure open is
releasing these models and that kind of
thing we we have to automate these
things because uh we see like when model
upgrades things typically do change um
it's not that it's better or worse it's
more that the model just behaves
differently to what the prompt was kind
of assuming and so we need to uh yeah
and fix and even if we change one of our
prompt you need to make sure that you
didn't all of a sudden open up or
something so how how much would you say
um if you
compare this type of feature development
to to you know traditional development
because there's you're saying there's a
lot of work into prompt engineering
authoring the prompts right and uh and
uh and there's some uh conventional code
writing right so what what would you say
like roughly the proportion is you know
how long time do you spend writing code
regular code and how long time do you
spend prompt engineering promp
engineering yeah
yeah I think it's it's hard to quantify
but uh it's it's definitely it is it is
very different to kind of your classical
uh software engineering um because uh
yeah you you have this blackbox now and
uh really the only way to have kind of
any guarantee on what's going on is to
have your test cases M um and u i I
think right now we're still writing a
lot of code in front of the model to
make sure that uh the output is as as we
expect and the the data types that are
going in are all good uh but I think as
as the models improve over time we can
have less like normal code and put more
into the prompt is kind of the reasoning
capabilities of these models
improve um so so I heard I heard a
I never told you that but I heard this
um we're talking about people where at
the very beginning we're starting
working with this and and inuring
prompts uh and people were were playing
around with this and uh it turns out
it's not easy to you as we discuss and I
heard that you were really good actually
uh at buying prompts like your prompts
were actually working better than other
we we kind of discussed and why is that
you know why is that good and maybe
maybe I don't know we don't know but
maybe there's something about uh being a
native speaker when you write things in
English and and maybe you get to be more
precise in in the wording and of things
maybe I don't know but what you saying
yeah I think it's definitely like an
unfair Advantage shall we say but uh I
think like even if you have a V1 of your
prompt um and as say you're not a native
speaker I think pass giving that passed
through the llm is is good because you
can you can ask it like please be more
concise with this language it'll fix any
kind of grammatical issues and that kind
of thing and then the text that is
produced will map uh more closely with
the text that it's been trained on so
hopefully then it performs uh a lot
better so on what you're saying is that
you could you can also use the llm to
improve your prompt oh yes that's what
you're saying say you WR the first
version yeah you WR the first version
and then especially maybe if you're not
a native speaker you can actually you s
a good ideas to use the LM and say hey
here's a prompt make it better or you
improve the language make it more
precise and uh it's also a technique to
to to get a better prompt exactly yeah
and I've seen quite often as well like
I've been talking to other engineers and
they're like ah how do I explain to the
model this concept and they write this
in a message to me and teams right and
I'm just like well you just explained it
to me so there you go you know and it's
like and um so like it's definitely like
one way to get started and then you can
always refine it sometimes oh this is
like a good word that actually conveys
the whole meaning but it's definitely it
does like scratch a different part of
the brain coming up these prompts
compared to just writing code like it's
they're both very creative processes I
think uh but this one is definitely Yeah
a different different area I would say
so could you show us some of these
prompts some of these system prompts we
have for for examp the chat the pilot
yeah yeah so unfortunately that is like
part of the our Microsoft uh IP uh at
the moment um so uh so no but um yeah
but if if you're kind of curious we do
have the the GitHub repo on uh BCT Tech
yeah uh and in there we do have some
prompting samples uh that we have for a
few different scenarios we'll put some
links in the in the description that' be
good um but that they're definitely not
ready for production use um but it gives
an idea of kind of the things you can do
uh with it and also like within the data
of of business Central um so it's just s
some nice end to end examples yeah all
right so yeah so talking about which so
what what would you what's what what
would you advise somebody who's new to
this type of uh you know AI programming
Andi AI development in BC where where
what would you say the the what would be
your advice to get started what do you
do you know maybe I have this idea and I
think maybe you know maybe I can use AI
to to do that so what's uh yeah yes
what's the flow so the well the very
first thing is uh so we actually have
some good documentation so I'll give a
link to that um but we we have uh this
co-pilot developer tools uh for business
Central uh and in there we have like a
lot of the boilerplate work uh already
done um so that you can easily call
these models uh send your prompts that
kind of thing and we also have so we
have that part right
with the model have some ux and
UI element so you can have a consistent
experience and that's super nice because
not only is it then consistent with NBC
but it's the exact same controls uh that
we use all across Microsoft um so if a
user is familiar with co-pilot in say
The Office Products they'll be familiar
with how to use it in business Central
if you use the the toolkit so uh it's
definitely a good starting point
um and I think the next uh point to keep
in mind is as I mentioned you should be
careful with uh where you are storing
your prompts um so right now you could
put them in the in say your key Vault if
if you're an appsource extension um and
that way when you distribute the app you
know people can't see the prompts inside
your code uh because it is IP at the end
of the day that's the the hard part not
so much the L Cod is thing yeah and and
um uh yeah exactly yeah yeah okay that's
uh okay then you get some uh some hints
on how to get started well thank you
Sam thank you for watching and let us
know in the comments if there are other
topics you would like us to talk about
we'll put some links in some of the
things we've been talking about during
this talk remember to subscribe and and
like that episode if you if you enjoyed
it yeah Che thank you for watching
thanks